# Nate King

# Full Stack Developer

Full-stack developer with fifteen years of IT systems and management experience, who recently left the IT world to level up their technical prowess by becoming a developer. Years have been spent honing in on the abilities to troubleshoot, problem-solve, and think out of the box when it comes to standing out in the technology field. Whether having been working autonomously, a part of teams or leading whole departments, all challenges were met head-on and accomplished with efficiency, care, and the highest quality.

#### **Work Experience**

### **Cultivation Technician**

Agri-Kind | Chester, PA

March 2020 - August 2020

- Support Master Grower by using past knowledge of plants to perform duties such as, but not limited to, plant tending, transplanting, feeding, defoliation, topping, flushing, inventory management, waste management, etc.
- Specialized in the fertigation system maintenance and operations. Developed and established a fertigation department along with best practices for the department. Oversaw 5000+ plants as well as a vast array of mothers and clones
- Responsible for nutrient replenishment in the automated fertigation system on a daily basis as well as making sure the nutrient mix is balanced and pH'ed per the Master Growers specifications in the mother, veg, and bloom stages.

# IT Manager

Revzilla Motorsports | Philadelphia, PA

March 2019 - March 2020

- Responsible for full scale IT department for 450+ user base and 4 facilities across the country
- Oversaw the IT needs of full scale web development, customer service, data analytic, marketing, and retail teams located across a national setting
- Support a multi-platform environment with Windows, Mac, & Linux in both client and PM/VM servers, including SAN's
- Lead admin for GSuite, Atlassian, Slack, LucidChart, Adobe, and many other tech business related services
- Renegotiated contracts and costs of goods from ISP's and third party vendors saving thousands in IT expenses
- Implemented a backup server solution in a facility that ran with no disaster recovery procedures
- Updated network to bring into PCI compliance
- Work side by side with web development team and DevOps teams

#### **Contact Details**

215.828.5606

□ natemking@gmail.com

www.natemking.dev

github.com/natemking

in linkedin.com/in/natemking

Philadelphia, PA

#### **Tech Skills**

Languages

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

MySQL

PowerShell

Frameworks

MongoDB

Express.js

React.is

Node.js

jQuery

BootStrap

Other Skills

Windows/OS X/Linux Server administration Atlassian Admin Azure/Cloud Services Hyper V/XenServer/VM AD. DNS. DHCP

O365 & GSuite administration Cisco & general networks

TCP/IP

#### **Personal Skills**

Project management
Team leading/management
Meticulous Documentation
Client relations
Highly organized
Bookkeeping

## IT Systems Administrator

PRG Real Estate | Philadelphia, PA

September 2013 - March 2019

- Provided IT system administration support via Level's 1,2, and 3 for PA based property management firm with national offices and a 300+ user base
- Acted as an implementation specialist for user support of the nation's leading property management software Yardi
- Operation and administration to multiple versions of Windows servers as well as AD, Office 365, Azure, and SharePoint
- Fully migrated and setup legacy server infrastructure from outdated physical hardware to virtual Hyper V environment in a failover cluster with multiple layers of redundancy on and off site
- Planned, organized, and executed a project to migrate SharePoint 2010 server to Office 365 cloud environment
- Acting liaison with multiple service providers to get the best deals in order to save the company money and improve efficiency
- Remote administration and setup of all users PC's. Brought entire corporation to domain architecture and implemented standards and practices never seen at PRG via group policy
- Traveled to multiple offices across the country to provide onsite installation, support, maintenance, and training for both hardware and software architecture
- Ran tech call center operations with a skill for effectively communicating with technical and non-technical staff as well as 3rd party consultants
- Onsite and remote PC repair. Implemented imaging process to streamline PC rollout efficiency

## Lead Desktop Support Technician

Premier Orthopaedics | Newtown Square, PA

January 2013 - September 2013

- Provided support via Level's 1,2, and 3 IT infrastructure for leading southeast Orthopedic group
- Maintained support for NextGen & Allscripts EHR software deployed via terminal server
- Maintained support on both PC and server side of PACS system
- Operation and administration to multiple Windows 2008 servers including AD and Exchange support
- Assisted implementation and began companywide rollout of Windows 7 deployment
- Experience with full migration of local EHR software to terminal server system
- Worked to keep all corporate systems within HIPAA compliance
- Provided remote desktop support to end users to effectively resolve their issues

# Network Technician / Asset & Supply Manager

Campus Technologies Inc | Philadelphia, PA

July 2005 - October 2012

#### **Example Projects**

## **Google Book Search**

GitHub: http://bit.ly/book-nmk-git Deploy: http://bit.ly/book-nmk

Summary - PWA that you can search for books using the Google Books API & save them to your library.

Responsibilities - Front-End -React. Backend server, routing, & database code

Languages/Tools - HTML, CSS, BootStrap, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, React

#### **Follow Your Money**

GitHub: http://bit.ly/git-fym Deploy: http://bit.ly/folo-yr-mon

Summary - Easy finance tracker with charts and categorical spending

Responsibilities - Front-End design & JS dynamics. Backend server routing, & database code

Languages/Tools - HTML, CSS, Javascript, , Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Webpack

#### Education

University of Pennsylvania's LPS Coding Accelerated Learning Program

2020 - 2021 Certificate in Full Stack Web Development